[Forging Justice]
[Episode 4]
Comrades,
are you court officers?
Yes.
We're all officers of the county court.
My name is Xia Yingjie.
Are you a villager here?
You could say so,
but I'm actually not.
Qiu Agui and I are from the same village.
We came here
through marriage at the same time.
Just like her, I was
beaten by my husband every day.
My husband was named Feng Dazhi.
Mrs. Feng, are you alright?
You know your man gambled, right?
Though he's dead now,
the debts he owed
must be paid off on time.
I'll give you one month.
No delay allowed.
Bastard,
why didn't you die sooner?
Slow down!
Even if you could
make it back now,
Mentor will have gotten off work.
Slow down! This is a downhill.
Go slower, slower.
[Nanyu County People's Court,
People's Procuratorate]
The lights are still on.
The lights are on.
What?
Careful.
Quick, Lihui!
Mentor!
Mentor...
What happened?
Where have you been all day?
Qiu Agui...
What's with Qiu Agui?
This is killing me.
I'd rather not go in.
I'm... exhausted.
How could they not even
thank us?
They just worked us to the bone.
I can understand them.
What was said by that woman we met later
is quite important.
Perhaps that can
really save Qiu Agui's life.
Of course you understand them,
since you're all the same,
with the same kind of stubbornness.
Are you saying
that I'm the same as Xia Yingjie?
I mean all of you.
Qiu Agui,
we're officers of the county court.
Today, you'll be interrogated.
You must be provide
candid answers,
without hiding anything.
Have I made myself clear?
Yes.
Why did you kill your husband?
I couldn't take the beatings anymore.
Was there no other reason?
No.
Officers,
I killed a man. I should die.
Please sentence me to death.
I just hope the government will
take good care
of my three poor children.
Qiu Agui,
you committed a crime.
The punishment on you
will be decided by the law.
That said, you must honestly
tell us all that happened
and withhold nothing.
Let me ask you again.
Did you kill Huang Liancang
only because he beat you?
Was there no other reason?
Right.
I couldn't stand the beatings anymore.
Qiu Agui, spill the truth.
Don't hide it anymore.
Xia.
-We already know...
-Xia.
To protect your children,
you must protect yourself first.
If anything is to your advantage,
make sure you say it honestly.
Only in this way can we
help you find a way to save your skin.
Animals.
Both men were animals.
But...
is her statement true?
I... guess so.
What reason did she have to tell
a massive lie?
What reason?
To spite her in-laws, that's what.
It's completely normal
for rural women
to stir up trouble and make things up.
Mr. Wang,
it's not fair to say that.
We already warned her
that lying would lead to
legal consequences.
Legal consequences?
Would she dare to testify?
As a widow living with her kids
at her in-laws',
would she dare to testify
to any connection
between her man and Huang Liancang?
You asked her,
and she wouldn't dare, right?
It's understandable that she has concerns.
A widow makes up
stories about her dead husband
probably due to hatred.
She got beaten all the time, didn't she?
I bet she's just venting her anger.
But when you get serious with her,
see—
she'd change her mind in no time.
We've seen plenty of this.
I beg to differ.
You're making a subjective assumption.
Well, look,
Mr. Wang is highly experienced.
The situation he mentioned truly exists.
But...
But what?
What do you have to do with this?
Don't you interfere.
I'm being subjective?
Aren't you also subjective
and opinionated?
Qiu Agui's husband gambled.
He lost and made his own daughter
sleep with some guy to pay his debts.
Now, both men are dead.
Isn't it odd?
Too much of a coincidence?
Dead men tell no tales.
We only have
the widow's side of the story,
and she dares not testify.
Qiu Agui herself never speaks of it.
If you were the judge,
would you believe it?
So you killed Huang Liancang
for the one and only reason
that he beat you?
Qiu Agui,
your husband lost money gambling,
so he decided to pay his debts by letting
his poker buddy
Feng Dazhi violate your daughter.
In order to keep your daughter
from further harm,
you had no choice
but to kill your husband.
Is it correct?
No!
How come at this point
you still have no idea
of protecting yourself?
Qiu Agui, think about it.
If you die,
-who will protect your daughter?
-Yingjie.
Let me say this again:
what you said didn't happen.
Don't you ever speak of it again.
Otherwise,
I won't stop haunting you
even if I become a ghost!
Xia Yingjie,
do you know
who you are?
All I know is that this is a fact
that can save her life.
But as a judge,
there's one thing you must know:
only facts recognized by the law
are considered facts.
Legally speaking,
what cannot be proven
simply didn't happen.
I'm not a judge yet.
But you're an officer of the court.
Let's back up for a moment.
If the story is proven true,
then morally speaking, there's some
justification
for Qiu Agui's act of killing,
though it doesn't
constitute justifiable defense.
It's not encouraged by the law,
but it should be understood.
This is a major mitigating circumstance.
You've got all the way down to that.
What else is there to discuss?
Let's leave it at that.
We're very busy.
This is indeed a tricky case.
But what if it's turned around?
If you turn the case around,
you'll be immortalized in history,
won't you?
How about this?
I'll try talking the higher-ups
into letting you
handle it,
so you'll be immortalized in history
and even make the news.
Go ahead and do it.
Tell the higher-ups.
See if I'll rise to fame.
Leave. Let's go.
And he calls himself a legal advisor.
So full of attitude.
Sorry.
Maybe we shouldn't have come.
Sorry for the trouble.
Have the electric fan fixed!
[Court President's Office]
How about
the court returns the files
and asks the procuratorate to conduct
a supplementary
investigation, Ding?
A supplementary investigation?
On what?
As of now,
the only witness
is Qiu Agui's daughter.
But she's still a minor.
Are you suggesting
the police and procuratorate
ask the child this,
"did your father make you
sleep with some guy?"
Do you wish to see
the child's testimony in court?
I'm telling you, if that happens,
in all probability,
not only
will Qiu Agui lose her life,
but also the child will bear
a stain on her life.
You think Qiu Agui would
like to see that happen?
That way, her sacrifice
will be i-in vain, right?
But, Ding,
even before the trial starts,
we've sentenced her to death.
Do you think this is right?
Enough.
Shumei,
listen to me.
If you really can't
bring yourself to go on with it,
we'll have someone else
preside with the case.
What difference does it make?
How else to approach it?
Given the current circumstances,
how about we say it is I
who instructs you to make a ruling?
Let me be the bad guy then.
Will that make you feel better?
Ding,
I just think there are justifiable reasons
for Qiu Agui to live!
The court president withheld his opinions?
His top concerns are not the law,
but social stability,
calls from the county government,
and his own job.
What about the lawyers?
Gloomy, too.
If the lawyers tell
all those stories
in court,
it should work, right?
Even God can't do anything to help
if Qiu Agui denies everything.
How about we talk to her daughter?
Let's first try
to resolve this internally.
Anyway, we can't
sit back and do nothing now.
Let's try to persuade Li Xiang again.
Yes, him.
He strikes me as a man
with a sense of justice.
We'll go to the procuratorate then.
It's essentially
their duty to find out the truth.
But we don't know anyone
in the procuratorate.
What does that matter?
Let's march straight to it.
It's just upstairs.
Li Xiang.
Why can't you understand?
They're college students
doing internships here.
Before long,
they will get back to Beijing.
Do you even know
the public opinion on this case?
Be that as it may,
we're Qiu Agui's lawyers.
Who are we being fair to
if we go to court
without meeting her even once?
Being fair to ourselves
would be enough already.
I'm warning you.
Try not to end up displeasing both sides
and getting in a dilemma.
Will you join me
in meeting Qiu Agui?
No.
I will.
I will g-go fetch some hot water.
You've waited for a while, huh?
Let's go.
Off to meet Qiu Agui.
Sure.
Chief Prosecutor.
They are asking us
to conduct a further investigation.
Have they taken our advice?
Off you go.
Here she comes.
The chief prosecutor
appreciates your concern.
Regarding this matter,
we will communicate with
the court again.
And then what?
"And then what"?
As I just told you,
we will communicate with
the court again.
But...
Chief Prosecutor Guan,
you...
I heard
your conversation.
Rest assured.
We promise
to get to the bottom of this matter.
Chief Prosecutor Guan,
we rashly came find you
since this matter is of great importance.
A perfunctory ruling
will lead to nothing
but the unjust death
of a mother who tries to
protect her children.
And those poor children
will be
reduced to orphans.
Moreover, truth will be completely buried.
I am begging you.
Please
give Qiu Agui a chance.
What if I give her one more chance
and she still
won't talk?
You are all
top-tier law students.
You should know
that any sympathy driven by
emotional inclination
has no evidentiary value.
Thanks, Chief Prosecutor Guan.
Hold on.
You're... Zhang Lihui?
Yes.
In fact, among
this batch of students,
you and Chen Yizhong
left quite a deep impression
on me.
Compassionate yet principled.
You see,
now, the crew of prosecutors
is in need of young members
like you, who can keep
their composure
and assert authority.
You're graduating soon, right?
Yes.
Think about joining us.
Sure.
Thank you.
How did it go?
Did Qiu Agui admit it?
No, she vehemently denied it.
She also forbade me
from bringing it up in court.
She said if I did,
she'd hunt me down even as a ghost.
Even without that element,
it still remains a fact that she was
abused for a long time.
Will it help if you
put up a proper defense
from this angle?
Lu,
are you teaching me
how to be a lawyer?
No, no.
We don't mean that.
Lu's just too worried.
I'll surely do my utmost.
But judging from the current situation,
a death penalty is a certainty.
Not to mention the huge impact
of this case right now.
Qiu's in-laws just won't back down.
Is there anything else we can do?
No, nothing.
This is what the world is like.
Not every problem
has a solution.
In my years as a lawyer,
this is what I feel deepest:
powerless.
I have an announcement to make.
That case
must go to trial tomorrow.
Qiu Agui was interrogated again,
but she firmly denied everything.
The trial starts tomorrow.
It's non-negotiable.
The location is
the county government auditorium.
Mentor.
Don't call me Mentor.
I don't deserve it.
Is anyone in there?
I'm from the court.
I remember you.
What do you want?
I...
I want nothing.
I was just passing by.
It's pouring outside.
Come in and take shelter!
Thank you.
How old are you?
I'm 14 years old.
Comrade Xia,
if you have anything to say,
say it now.
Or it'll be too late, since the trial
starts tomorrow.
It's true that all women
have endured a lot of hardship,
but this child
has really
suffered too much.
You know what?
Sometimes I have a strong urge to swear.
And I even want to hit someone.
That I can tell.
How about you yell at me,
and then you hit me?
I take that back.
It's pretty dangerous.
I...
I can't bring myself to swear.
Let me do it for you.
Damn it!
Fang Shumei, come out here!
My son's running a fever.
How could you, as his mom,
leave him unattended
and make me care for him instead?
Fang Shumei!
Come out here!
Here I come!
Why are you here?
Did you drink again?
Go home now.
I have to go to the court right away.
Quick. Go home now.
What are you doing?
My son's running a fever.
What do you think you're doing?
Hurry.
Let go of me!
Let go!
How could you assault others?
Leave me alone!
Mind your own business!
Stop!
Are you alright?
Go home with me.
Xia.
Xia, are you alright?
Stop. Stop it now!
Why did you have to drink?
Stop!
What do you think
you are doing?
What are you up to?
Where do you think you are?
Court Pres. Ding,
h-he just drank...
Shut up!
Do you know where you are?
What's this place?
Let's stay away.
This is a county court,
a state judicial organ.
But you attacked my people
and precious college students here.
You are way out of line!
Court Pres. Ding, he's drunk.
Y-You don't get to speak!
She's my wife,
so she's mine.
Everyone here is my people!
Talent for the state!
I can have you executed.
You believe it or not?
Go home already.
Hurry.
Off you go!
The trial starts soon.
Just go home now.
Get a move on!
What?
Haven't you seen enough?
Get out of here.
Stay as far as possible.
Got it?
Mentor, how are you holding up?
I'm doing fine.
Xia,
are you alright?
I'm sorry.
Don't say that.
Put this away.
Yes.
Are you nervous?
You will get used to it.
Put this away too.
Mentor,
is this the only way
Qiu Agui's case going to end?
The county auditorium is cleared today
for us to use as a courtroom.
Do you know what that means?
Be quick.
[Defendant]
Stand up!
Fang Shumei and Xia Yingjie
seem a bit off.
Did they get into a fight,
the mentor and the mentee?
Xia Yingjie can't be that reckless,
can she?
Be seated.
In the case of Nanyu County
People's Procuratorate
[Presiding Judge]
versus Qiu Agui for intentional homicide,
court is now in session.
Bring in the defendant.
Murderers deserve to die!
Order! Order!
She's a murderer!
Order in the court!
You'll die a terrible death!
Sit down!
Be seated, all of you.
What a vile woman!
Given that the defendant
was always law-abiding
and submissive,
that this is her first offense
and an isolated incident, that she showed
a good attitude
in admitting her guilt after her arrest,
and that she truthfully confessed
to all her criminal acts...
How dare you spew nonsense!
You damn bastard!
What's this about?
Liar!
You'll die a horrible death!
What's all this about?
You're no good either!
Get out!
You'll die a horrible death!
You damn bastard!
We humbly implore the court
to be lenient on the defendant,
in light of her role as a mother
supporting three underaged children.
What are you doing?
Good!
-Serves him right!
-Good one!
Quiet!
Well done!
Discipline!
Back to your seat!
I won't wipe it.
I'll leave it on!
Are you satisfied now?
Good for Wang Benshan.
He's acting like a real man.
How were those things brought in?
Whoever disrupts the court order
will be removed.
Have I made myself clear?
[Defendant]
Li Xiang.
You saw that, right?
Wake up, Tolstoy.
Defendant,
the indictment charges you
with the murder
of your husband, Huang Liancang.
Do you plead guilty?
Yes, I plead guilty.
I'm prepared to die for his life.
I only ask for my three children
to be taken good care of.
How dare you talk about the kids!
Those in the gallery,
without my permission,
you may not speak.
Take this as a warning.
Qiu Agui,
you and your husband
were married for over 10 years,
and you had three children.
How could you bring yourself to kill him?
What was your motive?
I...
Are you doing this on purpose?
What are you trying to get out of her?
Are you secretly helping her?
This is your second warning!
Qiu Agui,
answer the question.
Huang Liancang beat me
every single day,
when he was happy or unhappy,
when he was drunk,
and when he lost money gambling.
He not only beat me,
but also our children.
So much so that we trembled
simply at the sight of him.
At that rate, we would've been
beaten to death by him.
Nonsense!
You're making nonsense!
Be seated!
If you disrupt the court order again,
I will have you removed.
Do you hear me?
This is your last warning.
Defendant Qiu Agui,
you said your husband abused you.
Is there any proof of it?
Men all beat their wives, don't they?
Should a man die
for just beating his wife?
Get her out!
This is unfair!
This is unjust!
I...
Get out!
I... I will stop yelling.
-I will.
-Wait!
Considering you are the victim's family,
I'll let it slide this time.
But I won't tolerate it next time.
Do you understand?
I'm asking if you understand.
Yes, I understand.
Be seated.
Defendant Qiu Agui, you claim
your husband abused you.
Besides the scars on your body,
is there any other evidence?
No.
Defense counsel,
do you have any evidence
of the defendant being abused
by her husband?
All we have here is a copy
of the indictment.
But the prosecutor's evidence materials
include relevant proof.
Please present the evidence.
Exhibit No. 8 is the defedant's
medical records.
They prove
that the defendant was hospitalized
three times
for injuries caused by beatings.
Based on what she told the doctors,
she was beaten by her husband.
Exhibit No. 9 is a testimony given
by Huangping Town Women's Federation,
proving that the defendant
sought help from the institute twice
for being beaten
by her husband.
In response, the Women's Federation
talked to her husband twice.
Exhibit No. 10 is three pledges
written by the victim Huang Liancang
at Shangliang Villagers' Committee,
in all of which
he admitted to
beating the defendant
and promised never to do it again.
Defendant and defense lawyers,
do you acknowledge
the evidence mentioned?
Yes, we do.
Defendant,
did you call the police for being abused
by your husband?
No, never.
Why?
I turned to the villagers' committee
and the Women's Federation for help.
After every time I did,
he'd beat me even harder.
S-So I got scared.
What was he like
when you killed him?
He got drunk again
and fell asleep.
I wouldn't have been able
to kill him if he hadn't been asleep,
since I was no match for him at all.
He weighed over 100 kilograms,
and I weighed less than 50.
This concludes the court investigation.
Presiding Judge...
What are you up to?
They're going to throw cabbage at you.
I have further submissions
to make in defense.
Go ahead.
It was doubtlessly wrong
for Qiu Agui to take a life,
but she did it for a reason.
All the evidence presented
just now has already proved
that the defendant suffered
long-term and brutal abuse
from the victim.
She must have run out of options
when she decided to kill.
How much did the murderer pay you?
You'll rot in hell!
Sit down!
That's right!
You'll rot in hell!
Sit down!
The court has
examined and confirmed these facts.
Defense counsel,
do you have new submissions to make?
Don't ask for trouble and end up
irritating everyone.
Yes.
I'd like to ask
the defendant questions.
Great.
Bravo.
I'll allow it.
Qiu Agui,
this is your last chance.
For the sake of yourself
and your three children,
please tell the court truthfully
as to the real reason
for your sudden intent to kill.
The real reason?
You're asking about the real reason?
Yes,
the real reason.
I...
Don't forget
that only when you stay alive
can you protect your children.
Even if
you have to serve time in prison,
as long as you stay alive,
they will still have hope and relief.
The real reason
was that Huang Liancang beat me
and I couldn't take it anymore.
That's all.
Thank you, Mr. Li.
Thank you, Presiding Judge.
The defendant of this case
failed to properly handle
family conflicts.
She intentionally and unlawfully
deprived another person of life,
displaying grave subjective malice.
The prosecution deeply sympathizes
with the defendant
for the long-term abuse she suffered,
but does not believe
that this constitutes a ground
for a lenient sentence.
Therefore,
the prosecution firmly requests
the defendant
be sentenced to death
in accordance with the law.
Defense counsel,
please state your final opinion.
The defense rests.
No, we don't.
The defendant's crime of killing
is unforgivable,
but she did it for a reason.
The victim
was greatly at fault first.
It is our belief
that this is a factor that may
serve to mitigate
the defendant's legal culpability.
Defendant Qiu Agui,
this is your one last chance to speak.
Do you have anything to say to the court?
I killed a man.
I'm ready to pay with my life.
I'm only begging my mother-in-law
and my mother
to take care of my three poor children
since they're going to become
completely parentless.
Fortunately, my daughter,
the eldest child, is 14 now.
She can give proper care
to her two younger brothers.
I beg you
not to marry her off too early,
so she can raise her two younger brothers.
For that, you have my utter gratitude.
Thank you.
I beg you.
The trial ends here.
The verdict will be announced
at a later date.
Take the defendant in custody.
Ma'am!
Wait a second!
Can we have
a little discussion
on some things?
We have no reason
to shield Qiu Agui.
On the contrary,
we're doing this in your
and your family's best interest.
The dead can't be brought back to life.
If Qiu Agui is sentenced to death,
her three children
will truly
lose both parents.
Besides,
the kids are growing up
and starting to get sensible.
If they see you
firmly demanding
a death penalty for their mother,
what will they think of you
when they grow up?
How about this?
We'll go to Qiu Agui's parents' place
to fight for as much compensation
as possible.
Then you can issue a letter of forgiveness
so she won't have to die.
Even if she gets a death sentence
with a reprieve
or life imprisonment,
which will keep her
behind bars all her life,
her children will still have hope
as long as she stays alive.
What do you say?
Thank you
for being so considerate of our family.
We all want what's the best
for these three kids,
right?
Such poor children.
Presiding Judge,
if you don't sentence Qiu Agui to death,
I'll kill myself
right at the gate of the court.
Mrs. Hu, Mr. Liu,
please share your opinions
on how to rule on this case.
Fang,
you are a presiding judge for the people.
You must not be biased
or speak for a murderer.
Imagine this.
If your son were hacked
to death by his wife,
could you forgive her
and let her live?
Could you not take revenge?
To be honest,
my son also beats his wife.
In Nanyu,
lots of men beat their wives.
I've been through the same thing.
Of course, abusing others
is certainly wrong.
But we can educate these men.
Wives can't kill their husbands
just over
some family conflicts.
If that becomes a norm,
won't there be many tragedies
in the future?
Mrs. Hu,
you're also a woman.
How can you say something like that?
No, I mean...
Mr. Liu.
Share your views, please.
Fang,
please forgive me.
What happened to Qiu Agui
reminded me of my mother.
Through all her life, she was
also beaten by my father.
Later, in her fifties, she...
she hanged herself.
Let me state my position first.
I agree...
to spare Qiu Agui's life.
So she really didn't get a death penalty?
She almost did.
The assessor I brought in,
Mrs. Hu,
was a total mistake.
Luckily, Lihui brought in Mr. Liu,
who finally said
something reasonable.
Two to one.
A death sentence with a reprieve.
The credit actually goes to Jianmin.
It was he who told me
that Mr. Liu was the kindest
among all assessors.
Thank you, Jianmin.
Not so soon.
Things are not looking up.
This case will
ultimately go to the judicial committee.
Just think about the current situation.
Are you implying that Qiu Agui will
still be executed?
I didn't say that.